Basic Criteria for Defining a Defect Opportunity
Welcome to this session on defect opportunities.
What I'd like to do is briefly spend a little bit of time, and look at the criteria
for defining a defect opportunity.
There's only three. They’re pretty simple. We’re going to cover them one at a time.
Criteria one. The Y variable must exist.
The Y variable must exist. A dependent variable must exist. That's pretty simple.
If you don't have a variable, it's not possible to realize a defect.
If there is no critical to quality characteristic, there can be no defect.
If a defect cannot be realized, a defect cannot exist.
If the defect cannot exist, then the circumstances are not favorable.
Think of this, an opportunity is a set of circumstances favorable to an end.
In this case, favorable to a defect.
Well, one of the circumstances is, the variable has to exist
in order to be favorable to creating a defect.
Therefore, if the circumstances are not favorable, there is no opportunity.
Criteria 2, the Y variable must be a scaled quantity.
If it is not a scaled quantity, right there, if it is not,
then a performance standard cannot be assigned. That simple.
If you can't measure it, you can't put a standard to it.
If there's no standard, you can't realize a defect.
And then again, if a defect cannot be realized, a defect cannot exist.
And if a defect cannot exist, well self-evident.
Finally, the third criteria. The Y variable must maintain a performance standard.
We just talked about that.
So, three criteria. It's pretty simple.
Describes a defect opportunity. Let's put these in bright red,
so we can really kinda see them here, real good.
These are three important criteria for defining a defect opportunity.
One, the Y variable must exist.
Two, not only must it exist, it must be scaler. It must have scale to it.
And three, on that performance scale, there has to be a standard.
So, you gotta have a variable. You gotta have a scale. You gotta have a standard.
If those three things are present, you got a defect opportunity.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.